

Yeo Ming Sern

Lead Software Engineer

Email: yeomingsern@gmail.com

Contact number: +(60)11-10768827

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mingsern

Address: Jalan PJU 1a/44, Ara Damansara, 47301 Petaling

Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 5 years of experience, specializing in Mobile App Development and Web/Backend Development using Flutter, Laravel, and React.js. An Exceptional team player with strong communication skills, fluent in English, Mandarin, and Malay. Holds a Computer Software Engineering Degree (BS) from Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR). Excited and hungry about technology and continuously learning to stay ahead.

EXPERIENCES



Lead Software Engineer

Lemmy Tech (https://lemmyhomes.com/)

Aug 2023 until now

Description

- Work closely with DevOps to set up the microservice deployment pipeline. Using Docker, Kubernetes (K8), RabbiMQ, Github actions, and AWS services to set up a QA and Production environment for the whole microservice architecture.
- Collaborate with the product owners and top management to plan project roadmap and timeline using Jira and Google Workspace.
- Write documentation and provide maintenance for all services.
- Guide team members whenever they need help in terms of technical skills and career development.
- Set up basic architecture wireframe for web and mobile development using React.js and Flutter.
- Practice code review, review, and merge team members' pull requests, and provide friendly feedback.

Key Achievement

 Coordinate tasks among DevOps and Software engineers, designing and developing the microservice and database structure using mostly Laravel, Node.js, React.js, and Flutter for the application layer and MySQL and PostgreSQL for the databases. And able to complete the first launch within 3 months.



Senior Software Engineer

KSK City Labs (https://www.kskgroup.com/)

Jan 2022 until Aug 2023 (1 year 8 months)

Description

- More responsibilities and roles have been given, working as a Back-end developer and Flutter developer, handling both back-end and front-end.
- Mostly worked on Laravel projects, as a helping hand to the Tech Lead, developing RESTful APIs for the mobile application, and refactoring legacy code with shorter and cleaner code by moving most of the code from Laravel v5 to v9, thousands of lines of code have been removed.
- Worked with multiple third-party vendors on integrating their systems into the mobile app, such as property access management, KONE lift APIs, voice/video calls similar to WhatsApp, and many more.
- Provide knowledge sharing to team members about type programming languages such as Typescripts to understand the importance of typing.
- Collaborate with the QA engineers to enhance tests with automation using Cypress,
 Flutter integration tests, and Postman API tests.
- Help solve feature deployment environment, provide a solution such as multi-environment deployment, work collaboration with DevOps, and demonstrate my innovation and problem-solving skills.
- Migrate and build CI/CD pipeline for mobile applications from Fastlane to CodeMagic to save costs and manpower in maintaining and writing Fastlane code.

Key Achievement

Worked on multiple projects, handling mobile, web, and APIs development with little
to no help. Mainly using Flutter, Laravel, and MySQL to build internal tools to
enhance the sales team, managing their leads and approvals between Top
Management. Efficiency improved by 90%.



Description

- Worked as a UI/UX designer, and Flutter developer. Single-handedly designed, developed, and deployed a smart home application from scratch using Figma, Flutter, and Laravel.
- Work closely with the Product Owner and Tech Lead on the product requirements and system design.
- Implement biometric login, WeChat login, and also pin code login similar to native iOS.
- Use existing RESTful APIs and integrate them into the mobile application using "dio".
- Able to revamp the entire codebase within 2 months to enhance the performance and security of the mobile application after reading and debugging the entire codebase left by previous employees during my probation period.
- Research, study and design more on software architectures, design patterns, and state management packages such as "flutter_riverpod"
 (https://pub.dev/packages/flutter_riverpod).
- Debugging and fixing mobile app to help solve memory leak issues and lower the number of renderings.
- Build CI/CD pipeline for mobile application using Fastlane, easily deploy the application to Apple App Store, Google Play Store, and Huawei App Gallery.

Key Achievement

 Received employee recognition for the year 2021. And been promoted to Senior Software Engineer.



Description

- Mainly working as a Back-end developer using Laravel and Ruby on Rails to develop multiple Open RESTful APIs for public and internal partners to use.
- Maintain legacy code, fix bugs and write clean code.
- Integrate multiple applications into the EasyStore system, such as Shopee and Lazada for merchants to easily sync their orders, products, and customers into these platforms.
- Designing, developing, testing, and deploying an e-commerce application using Flutter framework(Dart).
- Write documentation on the whole architecture for the mobile application.
- Using software tools such as Sentry, Graphana, and Kibana to monitor and keep track of logs and errors.
- Research and study more on software architectures, design patterns, and state
 management such as "Provider", "Bloc", and "GetX". And implement it onto the
 mobile app to help solve memory leak issues and lower the number of renderings.

Key Achievement

Explore more on mobile cross-platform development using Flutter, Firebase, UI/UX
design principles as well as native Android and iOS code with little to no help and
able to complete and release the first mobile application product for EasyStore within
3 months for iOS and Android.



Description

- Mainly working as a Back-end developer using Laravel(PHP) and Ruby on Rails(Ruby) to develop multiple Open RESTful APIs for public and internal partners to use.
- Expose to the basic foundation of programming languages, frameworks, practices, and tools used on a daily basis, such as versioning control(Git), GitHub, Scrum,
 Sourcetree, Slack, MySql Workbench, and many more.
- Learn about how to debug errors and track them using tools such as Sentry.
- Develop an analytic plugin for merchants, so they can easily install Google Analytics and Facebook Pixel to help track conversations on the online store.
- Developed a mini e-commerce application to help merchants increase sales on their e-commerce website using Vue.js and Laravel.

Key Achievement

• EasyStore offered me a full-time permanent position as a Software Engineer before my university graduation.

PROJECTS

Flutter Package (flutter_bounceable)

Sep 2021

- https://pub.dev/packages/flutter_bounceable
- A simple, interactive, and customizable on-tap bounce animation that can be wrapped on any widget that you like.

EDUCATIONS



Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR)

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Software Engineering

May 2017 until May 2020 (3 years)

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

Cyber Security Awareness: Social Engineering

LinkedIn

Issued Oct 2022

Software Architecture Foundation

LinkedIn

Issued Oct 2022

MDEC-Microsoft Premier-Pride Challenge 2019 Artificial Intelligence Modules

Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation (MDEC)

Issued 2019

Completion of MDEC-Intel® Al Academy

Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation (MDEC)

Issued 2019

Fusionex Data Challenge (3rd runner-up)

Fusionex Group

Issued 2019

HONORS & AWARDS

Champion in LKC FES Final Year Poster Competition

Jun 2020

3rd Runner Up in Fusionex Data Challenge

Jul 2019

Dean's List

Jan 2019